Douglas J. Wright

mrdougwright@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mrdougwright (323) 206-8549

Ex-marketer turned Ruby on Rails Dev who now enjoys functional programming in React. Full stack dev with a love for data-driven decisions, including A/B testing, analytics, and kanban-driven tech cycles. I've worked at small and large startups with several different business initiatives and tech stacks.

EXPERIENCE:

Participant Media, Los Angeles

2016-Present

- SR SOFTWARE ENGINEER
 - Overhaul Rspec test suite for Rails 4 application
 - Build article query API for Apache Solr database
 - · Reduce technical debt, code complexity and squash bugs!

Bedside, Los Angeles

2015-2016

HEAD OF ENGINEERING

- Lead engineering team and HIPAA security & certifications
- Designed architecture and built out Rails 4 web app and Ionic mobile app
- Built API for a Health Data company using Ruby and SQL Server

CommitChange, Oakland

2014-2015

DIRECTOR OF PLATFORM

- Responsible for product development & direction as well as marketing analytics & growth
- · Backend and Frontend engineering, using custom JavaScript libraries and Rails
- Integrated marketing technologies and APIs, such as CustomerIO, FullContact, CloseIO, & GA
- Introduced in-house scrum development planning and product roadmap

Bloc, San Francisco

2013-2014

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- · Backend and Frontend engineering, with focus on TDD and Ruby on Rails conventions
- · Built the coupon referral program, CRM API integrations, and analytics dashboard
- Worked closely with Dir. of Marketing to design, track and implement A/B optimizations
- Experience in Ruby, Rails, AngularJS, Customer.io, Segment.io, Mixpanel, Optimizely and GA

New Relic, San Francisco

2012-2013

CONVERSION OPTIMIZATION MANAGER

- Own analytics, SEO and A/B testing for conversion
- · Created and implemented over 100 website tests with a 40% win rate and 20% conversion lift
- Created a testing plan and learning center to gain insight into every test
- Implemented SEO techniques to ensure steady traffic during transition of launching new website

Get Satisfaction, San Francisco

2011-2012

FREEMIUM MARKETING MANAGER

- A/B tested plans pages to increase signup conversion rate by 12%
- Reduced churn by 5% after evaluating customer feedback and creating product improvements
- · Work with product manager and UX director to enhance product features to the market
- Create, deploy and analyze email campaigns and other outreach marketing efforts

EDUCATION: Santa Clara University, Santa Clara

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, BUSINESS

2003

Academy of Art University, San Francisco

MASTER OF FINE ARTS 2008

TECHNICAL Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, mySQL, Git, React, JavaScript, ES6, **SKILLS:** Database Tools, CRM systems, SalesForce, Optimization Tools.

EXTRA: Wrote a Ruby book for kids: <u>rubykin.com</u>

Coding blog: dogwithrug.com

Projects: doug.io